Hello English learners, welcome back to another podcast with us here at EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎回到EnglishPod的播客节目。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today we're going to be looking at a very popular topic, something that everyone has
今天我们要讨论一个非常热门的话题，每个人一生中至少
to do at least once in their life.
都要做一次的事情。
That's right, we're talking about mobile phones and getting a mobile phone plan.
没错，我们要聊的是手机和办理手机套餐。
Right, so you have a mobile phone, you need to get a plan or you need to do something
对，所以你有手机，你需要办个套餐或者做点什么
in order to make it work, right?
才能让它能用，对吧？
Yes, and in this lesson we're going to learn some language to help you do that.
是的，在这节课中，我们会学习一些语言来帮助你做到这一点。
Alright, so let's start with the language on Vocabulary Preview.
好的，那么我们先从词汇预览中的语言开始。
Vocabulary Preview.
词汇预览。
In the dialogue, we're going to compare two types of mobile phone plans, the prepaid plan
在对话中，我们将比较两种手机套餐：预付费套餐
and the monthly rate plan.
和月费套餐。
Okay, so we have two types of plans, prepaid.
好的，我们有两种套餐：预付费。
Prepaid plan.
预付费套餐。
Okay, a prepaid plan.
好的，预付费套餐。
Well, a prepaid plan, basically, just like the name suggests, you pay before you use
嗯，预付费套餐，基本上就像名字说的那样，你先付钱再使用
the minutes.
分钟数。
So maybe you have to buy a card and then you can use maybe 20 minutes or 30 minutes or
所以你可能需要买一张卡，然后可以用20分钟、30分钟或者
100 minutes.
100分钟。
Exactly.
没错。
And then when you run out of money or you use all your minutes, you can buy another
然后当你钱用完了或者分钟数用光了，你可以再买一张
card and like that.
卡，就这样。
Yeah, but the monthly rate plan is different.
是的，但月费套餐不一样。
So the monthly rate plan, you have to pay each month.
月费套餐，你每个月都要付钱。
Right, at the end of each month.
对，每个月月底。
At the end of each month.
每个月月底。
And what do you pay?
那你付什么？
You pay for everything you used.
你为你用过的所有东西付钱。
You get a bill at the end of the month.
你月底会收到账单。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay, so very interesting.
好的，非常有趣。
These are the ways that mobile phone plans usually work.
这些是手机套餐通常的运作方式。
And well, now it's time for us to listen to this dialogue for the first time.
嗯，现在是时候第一次听这段对话了。
We are going to be listening as a shopper is looking to buy maybe a mobile phone or
我们会听到一位顾客想买手机或者
get a mobile phone plan.
办手机套餐。
Yeah I just moved here and I'd like to activate my cell phone and I'm not sure if I should
是的，我刚搬到这里，想激活我的手机，但不确定应该
go with a prepaid plan or a monthly rate plan.
选预付费套餐还是月费套餐。
I see.
我明白了。
Well, can I have a look at your phone?
好的，我能看看你的手机吗？
Unfortunately this phone can't be used in the US.
不幸的是，这部手机在美国不能用。
It's not compatible with our 3G network.
它不兼容我们的3G网络。
What really?
真的吗？
I don't really want to have to buy a new phone.
我真的不想买新手机。
Well you're in luck.
那你运气好。
You see, if you sign up for our 3 year plan, we'll throw in a handset for free.
你看，如果你签我们的三年套餐，我们会免费送一部手机。
Really?
真的吗？
What's the catch?
有什么陷阱？
There's no catch.
没有陷阱。
You just choose a plan, sign a 3 year contract and that's it.
你只要选个套餐，签个三年合同就行了。
Actually, we're running a special promotion right now and we're giving away a Blackberry
实际上，我们现在正在搞特别促销，赠送一部黑莓
Curve with our special mega value $40 plan.
Curve手机，搭配我们的超值40美元套餐。
So what does this plan include?
那这个套餐包括什么？
Well you get 900 anytime minutes and you can also enjoy free mobile to mobile calling to
嗯，你有900分钟任意时段通话，还可以享受免费网内通话，
other Telmobile clients.
打给其他Telmobile客户。
A thousand text messages per month and unlimited evening and weekend minutes.
每月1000条短信，以及无限晚间和周末分钟数。
Oh, and we also offer a rollover option.
哦，我们还提供滚动选项。
Wow.
哇。
All this for $40 per month?
所有这些只要每月40美元？
That's right.
没错。
Plus the activation fee and the emergency services fee, the monthly service fee and
再加上激活费、紧急服务费、月服务费以及
any charges for extra minutes and...
超时分钟的费用等等……
Well it sounds like a lot more than $40, doesn't it?
嗯，听起来可不止40美元，对吧？
This is very common.
这很常见。
They always say that it's a very low price and they always have these hidden charges,
他们总是说价格很低，但总有这些隐藏费用，
right?
对吧？
You're right.
你说得对。
So why don't we look at some of the language they were using in the dialogue now in Language
那我们不如现在看看对话中用到的一些语言，在语言
Takeaway.
要点部分。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
All right, on Language Takeaway today we're going to be looking at 4 very basic words
好的，在今天的语言要点中，我们要看四个非常基础的词，
that are used in this whole mobile phone context and the first one is activate.
它们都用在手机这个语境中，第一个是“激活”。
To activate my cell phone.
激活我的手机。
All right, so you have to activate your cell phone.
好的，所以你得激活你的手机。
That's right.
没错。
You have to make the cell phone work.
你得让手机能用。
So basically you make it work.
基本上就是让它工作起来。
Now can you only apply this to mobile phones?
这个词只能用在手机上吗？
No, there's many things that you must activate to make work.
不，很多东西都需要激活才能用。
For example, you must activate your computer software.
比如，你得激活你的电脑软件。
Okay, or maybe you have to activate your credit card.
好的，或者你可能得激活你的信用卡。
Or activate your bank account.
或者激活你的银行账户。
So usually you do this for the first time before you start using it.
所以通常是在第一次使用前做这件事。
But imagine your mobile phone is sleeping, right?
但想象你的手机在“睡觉”，对吧？
And you need to activate it to make it start working.
你需要激活它让它开始工作。
But you only do it once.
但你只做一次。
Right, only once.
对，只一次。
Okay.
好的。
We talk about mobile phone or we say the cell phone, but this also has a specific name,
我们说到手机，或者叫它移动电话，但它也有一个特定的名称，
right?
对吧？
That's right.
没错。
A handset.
手机（handset）。
Handset.
手机。
A handset.
So the device, the phone, you can call it a handset.
所以这个设备，电话，你可以叫它手机。
Exactly.
没错。
All right, a very easy word, but it's kind of a little bit more technical.
好的，一个很简单的词，但有点更技术性。
Yeah.
是的。
Now, one of the things they were talking about with this monthly rate plan was a rollover
现在，他们讨论月费套餐时提到的一个东西是滚动
option.
选项。
Rollover.
滚动。
A rollover option.
滚动选项。
So what is this rollover option about?
那这个滚动选项是怎么回事？
Well, okay, I'll give you an example.
嗯，好吧，我给你举个例子。
Let's say you have 500 minutes each month.
假设你每个月有500分钟。
And you only use four of them in this month.
而这个月你只用了400分钟。
100 of those minutes can roll over, can move over to the next month, so now you have 600
其中100分钟可以滚动，可以转到下个月，所以你现在有600
minutes.
分钟。
So basically, the minutes that you don't use, you can still use the following month.
所以基本上，你没用的分钟数，下个月还能用。
Right.
对。
Okay, so that's a rollover plan.
好的，那就是滚动套餐。
Now, we might recognize the verb to roll over, right?
现在，我们可能认识动词“滚动”，对吧？
Right, so it's very similar to physically move from one place to another.
对，所以它很像物理上从一个地方移到另一个地方。
Yep.
是的。
All right, rollover.
好的，滚动。
And now, in the end, we talked about many types of fees.
现在，最后，我们谈到了很多种费用。
That's right, activation fee.
没错，激活费。
Okay, or we also had emergency services fee.
好的，或者我们还有紧急服务费。
So what is a fee?
那什么是费用？
A fee is the amount of money you must pay for a service.
费用是你为一项服务必须支付的金额。
Okay, so this is important.
好的，这很重要。
It's for a service.
它是针对服务的。
Yeah, you can't pay a fee for something you can touch.
是的，你不能为摸得着的东西付费用。
Okay, so if I go to the store, I don't say, what is the fee of this bottle of water?
好的，所以如果我去商店，我不会说，这瓶水的费用是多少？
Right.
对。
What's the fee for filling this bottle of water?
装这瓶水的费用是多少？
Okay, so for a service.
好的，所以是针对服务。
Yes, for an action.
是的，针对一个动作。
All right, very good.
好的，非常好。
So I think it's time for us to listen to this dialogue again.
所以我想是时候再听一遍这段对话了。
We're going to slow it down because it was a little bit fast, and then we'll come back
我们会放慢速度，因为之前有点快，然后我们再回来
and look at some great phrases.
看一些好用的短语。
Hi there.
你好。
Can I help you?
需要帮忙吗？
Yeah, I've just moved here, and I'd like to activate my cell phone.
是的，我刚搬到这里，想激活我的手机。
And I'm not sure if I should go with a prepaid plan or a monthly rate plan.
我不确定应该选预付费套餐还是月费套餐。
I see.
我明白了。
Well, can I have a look at your phone?
好的，我能看看你的手机吗？
Unfortunately, this phone can't be used in the US.
不幸的是，这部手机在美国不能用。
It's not compatible with our 3G network.
它不兼容我们的3G网络。
What?
什么？
Really?
真的吗？
I don't really want to have to buy a new phone.
我真的不想买新手机。
Well, you're in luck.
嗯，你运气好。
You see, if you sign up for our three-year plan, we'll throw in a handset for free.
你看，如果你签我们的三年套餐，我们会免费送一部手机。
Really?
真的吗？
What's the catch?
有什么陷阱？
There's no catch.
没有陷阱。
You just choose a plan, sign a three-year contract, and that's it.
你只要选个套餐，签个三年合同就行了。
Actually, we're running a special promotion right now, and we're giving away a BlackBerry
实际上，我们现在正在搞特别促销，赠送一部黑莓
Curve with our special mega-value $40 plan.
Curve手机，搭配我们的超值40美元套餐。
So what does this plan include?
那这个套餐包括什么？
Well, you get 900 anytime minutes, and you can also enjoy free mobile-to-mobile calling
嗯，你有900分钟任意时段通话，还可以享受免费网内通话，
to other Telmobile clients, 1,000 text messages per month, and unlimited evening and weekend
打给其他Telmobile客户，每月1000条短信，以及无限晚间和周末
minutes.
分钟数。
Oh, and we also offer a rollover option.
哦，我们还提供滚动选项。
Wow.
哇。
All this for $40 per month?
所有这些只要每月40美元？
That's right.
没错。
Plus the activation fee, the emergency services fee, the monthly service fee, oh, and any
再加上激活费、紧急服务费、月服务费，哦，还有任何
charges for extra minutes and...
超时分钟的费用等等……
Well, you know, there are some interesting phrases in this dialogue, and a lot of them
嗯，这段对话中有一些有趣的短语，其中很多
can be used when you're talking about a negotiation or a contract or a deal.
可以在谈论谈判、合同或交易时使用。
All right, great.
好的，太好了。
So let's take a look at these phrases in Fluency Builder.
那我们来看看流利度提升中的这些短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度提升。
Okay, the first phrase that we have on Fluency Builder today was the problem that she had
好的，今天流利度提升中的第一个短语是她手机的问题
with her mobile phone was that it wasn't compatible with a 3G network.
是不兼容3G网络。
Okay, to be compatible with.
好的，与……兼容。
To be compatible with.
与……兼容。
Now this word compatible means that it works well with something else.
这个词“兼容”的意思是它与其他东西配合得好。
Exactly.
没错。
Now there's a lot of things that you can use this phrase compatible with, together with.
现在有很多东西可以用这个短语“与……兼容”，一起用。
You know, people, things.
你知道，人、事物。
So why don't we hear a few examples now.
那我们不如现在听几个例子。
Example one.
例子一。
Our application is compatible with most smartphones.
我们的应用程序兼容大多数智能手机。
Example two.
例子二。
My roommate and I are just not compatible.
我和室友就是合不来。
All she ever does is study, and I like to stay up late and party.
她整天只知道学习，而我喜欢熬夜开派对。
Example three.
例子三。
I'm sorry, your computer is not compatible with our software.
抱歉，你的电脑不兼容我们的软件。
It's too old.
它太旧了。
Okay, great example.
好的，很好的例子。
So compatible with, very clear, and it's very useful.
所以“与……兼容”，非常清楚，而且很有用。
That's right.
没错。
Now, what about the next phrase?
那下一个短语呢？
Well, you know, the girl was hearing about all of these great things that are included
嗯，你知道，那个女孩听到合同里包含的所有这些好东西，
in the contract, and she asked, what's the catch?
她问：“有什么陷阱？”
What's the catch?
有什么陷阱？
So she was asking for the catch.
所以她是在问陷阱。
What is the catch?
陷阱是什么？
Well, good thing you asked.
嗯，你问得好。
A catch is something negative, something that's hidden, that makes the deal seem not so great.
陷阱是负面的东西，隐藏的东西，让交易看起来没那么好。
Okay, so if somebody offers me a new car.
好的，所以如果有人免费给我一辆新车。
They say, you can have this new for free.
他们说，你可以免费得到这辆新车。
Okay, well, that seems too good to be true.
好的，嗯，那听起来好得不像真的。
So what is the catch?
所以陷阱是什么？
The catch is that I can only drive it at night.
问题是我只能在晚上开它。
Okay, that's kind of annoying.
好吧，这有点烦人。
Right.
没错。
So that's the catch.
所以这就是问题所在。
There's like a condition.
就像有个条件。
Yep.
是的。
Now, she asked about the catch, and well, she said, well, there's no catch, you know,
现在，她问到了“问题”，然后她说，嗯，没什么问题，你知道，
you just signed the contract.
你只是签了合同。
And then the salesman told the lady that she is in luck.
然后销售员告诉那位女士她运气好。
You're in luck.
你运气好。
To be in luck.
运气好。
Well, okay, I think we can really understand the meaning, right?
嗯，好吧，我觉得我们都能理解意思，对吧？
When you're in luck, something lucky has happened.
当你运气好时，就是发生了幸运的事。
Right.
没错。
You're having good fortune.
你运气不错。
But how do we use it?
但我们怎么用它呢？
So maybe you're looking for a very special bottle of wine for dinner tonight.
比如，你今晚想找一瓶特别的葡萄酒来配晚餐。
Yep, it's very rare.
是的，它很稀有。
Okay, and you go into this little store, and all of a sudden, you're in luck.
好吧，你走进这家小店，突然之间，你运气来了。
You found it there.
你找到了它。
Exactly.
正是。
Okay.
好的。
This phrase is actually most commonly used in the second person.
这个短语实际上最常用于第二人称。
You're in luck.
你运气好。
You are in luck.
You are in luck tonight.
你今晚运气好。
Yeah, and usually when someone asks you for something, then you say, you're in luck.
是的，通常当有人向你请求某物时，你会说，你运气好。
You're in luck.
你运气好。
I have it.
我有。
Or you're in luck.
或者你运气好。
I have the very last one.
我有最后一个。
Exactly.
正是。
All right, and now, to end a fluency builder, we have one more phrase.
好了，现在，为了结束这个流利度练习，我们还有一个短语。
And so it was when the salesman said, we'll throw in a handset for free.
所以当销售员说，我们会免费赠送一个手机时，就是这样。
All right, to throw something in.
好的，免费赠送某物。
So if she signs the contract, he will throw in a free handset.
所以如果她签了合同，他会免费赠送一个手机。
It means to include something for free.
意思是免费包含某物。
Okay, so you can say, if you buy this house, I'll throw in the dog for free.
好的，所以你可以说，如果你买这栋房子，我会免费把狗送给你。
Right?
对吧？
So to throw in, to include for free.
所以“throw in”就是免费包含。
Right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
All right, so great phrases, and I think we understand them now.
好了，这些短语很棒，我想我们现在都理解了。
So let's listen to this dialogue for the very last time.
那么让我们最后一次听这段对话。
Yeah, I just moved here, and I'd like to activate my cell phone, and I'm not sure if I should
是的，我刚搬到这里，想激活我的手机，我不确定应该选
go with a prepaid plan or a monthly rate plan.
预付费套餐还是月费套餐。
I see.
我明白了。
Well, can I have a look at your phone?
嗯，我能看看你的手机吗？
Unfortunately, this phone can't be used in the US.
不幸的是，这部手机在美国不能用。
It's not compatible with our 3G network.
它不兼容我们的3G网络。
What?
什么？
Really?
真的吗？
I don't really want to have to buy a new phone.
我真的不想买新手机。
Well, you're in luck.
嗯，你运气好。
You see, if you sign up for our three-year plan, we'll throw in a handset for free.
你看，如果你签我们的三年套餐，我们会免费赠送一个手机。
Really?
真的吗？
What's the catch?
有什么问题吗？
There's no catch.
没问题。
You just choose a plan, sign a three-year contract, and that's it.
你只需选个套餐，签个三年合同，就这样。
Actually, we're running a special promotion right now, and we're giving away a BlackBerry
实际上，我们现在有个特别促销，正在赠送黑莓
Curve with our special mega value $40 plan.
Curve手机，搭配我们的特惠超值40美元套餐。
So what does this plan include?
那么这个套餐包括什么？
Well, you get 900 anytime minutes, and you can also enjoy free mobile-to-mobile calling
嗯，你得到900分钟任意时段通话，还可以享受免费网内通话
to other Telmobile clients, 1,000 text messages per month, and unlimited evening and weekend
给其他Telmobile客户，每月1000条短信，以及无限晚间和周末
minutes.
分钟。
And we also offer a rollover option.
我们还提供结转选项。
Wow.
哇。
All this for $40 per month?
所有这些只要每月40美元？
That's right.
没错。
Plus the activation fee and the emergency services fee, the monthly service fee, and
再加上激活费和紧急服务费、月服务费，以及
any charges for extra minutes and...
额外分钟的费用和……
Mobile phones.
手机。
This is very common in the United States, right?
这在美国很常见，对吧？
These monthly plans.
这些月费套餐。
Yeah.
是的。
Most places where I have lived, it's much more common to pay as you go, right?
我住过的大多数地方，更常见的是随用随付，对吧？
To have a prepaid plan.
用预付费套餐。
But in the States, almost everyone goes with the monthly plan.
但在美国，几乎每个人都用月费套餐。
Maybe it's because in order to have a monthly plan, you need to have a credit card.
也许是因为要办月费套餐，你需要有信用卡。
You might be onto something.
你可能说到点子上了。
Right?
对吧？
So if you don't have a credit card, or maybe you're 18, you can't get a monthly plan.
所以如果你没有信用卡，或者你才18岁，你就办不了月费套餐。
So you gotta do this prepaid plan.
所以你得用预付费套餐。
Yeah.
是的。
Another interesting thing that I've noticed when living in different countries and seeing
另一个有趣的事情是，我在不同国家生活时注意到
mobile phone habits, Americans and North Americans respond very differently to a ringing mobile
手机使用习惯，美国人和北美人对手机铃声的反应
phone than other people do.
和其他人很不一样。
How so?
怎么不一样？
For example, if I was in a meeting in America and my phone rang and I answered it, people
比如，如果我在美国开会时手机响了，我接了，人们
might think that I was very rude to answer the phone in a meeting.
可能会觉得我在会议上接电话很粗鲁。
But here, when we're living in China, it's totally normal.
但在这里，我们住在中国时，这完全正常。
Everyone does it.
每个人都这么做。
That's the polite thing to do, answer your phone.
接电话才是礼貌的做法。
Right.
没错。
And I think that's absolutely true, and maybe it's because in North America, you have this
我认为这绝对是真的，也许是因为在北美，你的手机有
voicemail option for your mobile phone.
语音信箱选项。
Yeah, and everyone has it.
是的，每个人都有。
Everyone has it.
每个人都有。
So if it's something very important, then the person will leave you a voicemail message
所以如果事情很重要，对方会给你留语音信息，
and then you will know what it's about or you can call them back.
然后你就知道是什么事，或者你可以回电。
But here, I guess, or in other countries, maybe they don't have that option, so they
但在这里，我猜，或者在其他国家，也许他们没有那个选项，所以他们
need to answer every call.
需要接每个电话。
Yeah, it's interesting.
是的，这很有趣。
An interesting sort of cultural difference in the way we use our phones.
一种有趣的关于我们使用手机方式的文化差异。
But what about listeners?
但听众们呢？
In your country, do you answer the phone immediately or do you let it ring?
在你们国家，你是立刻接电话还是让它响着？
Right, or maybe do you see who's calling and maybe just not answer it.
没错，或者也许你看是谁打来的，然后就不接。
Yeah, screen your calls.
是的，筛选来电。
To screen a call.
筛选来电。
Yeah.
是的。
So come to our website, EnglishPod.com, let us know what your mobile phone habits are
所以来我们的网站EnglishPod.com，告诉我们你的手机使用习惯是什么，
and also if you have any questions or doubts.
以及如果你有任何问题或疑问。
Yeah, Marco and I are always there to answer your questions, so until next time, thanks
是的，Marco和我总是在那里回答你的问题，所以下次再见，感谢
for listening and goodbye.
收听，再见。
Goodbye.
再见。